Ali Yazdi

Dept. Computer Engineering Amirkabir University, Hafez Ave., Tehran, Iran ma.yazdi75@gmail.com • ma.yazdi75@aut.ac.ir • (+98) 912 037 1375 • https://aliyazdi75.github.io

ABOUT ME

I have been working as a Flutter developer and mobile team leader for two years. I am a CS graduate who interests in using Artificial Intelligence and Software Engineering in my work. I am an open-source advocate who helps developers to solve their problems in development. I am finding a better opportunity and willing to relocate to the new country.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mate Machine Inc., North Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada - Remote

Jun 2020 - Present

Flutter

Preparing the Flutter application for the first launch.

Tarafdari, Tehran, Iran

Mar 2019 - May 2020

Flutter, Drupal, Laravel, MySQL

- Working as mobile application team leader at one of the most popular sport social media.
 - Developing requirement APIs.
 - R&D about Flutter framework and migrating the android application to Flutter application that is including multimedia content, live score matches, sports TV streaming with live chat on the socket.

EDUCATION

Amirkabir University of Technology, (Tehran Polytechnic), Tehran, Iran

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering, Software

Sep 2015 – Jan 2020

- Thesis: Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System
- Adviser: Prof. Mohammad Rahmati

Adab High School. Tehran, Iran

• GPA: 19.31 / 20.00

Diploma in Mathematics and Physics

Sep 2011 – Jun 2014

HONORS & AWARDS

• First Place in the 12th Iran Web and Mobile Festival (IWMF)
For the Best Sport Mobile Application among 7k applications

Feb 2020

- Most installed sport application in Iran
 May 2020
 In my first job, we could reach more than 200k active users on the Google Play Store after migrating to the flutter
- Ranked in top 0.2% among more than 180K participants

 In Nation-Wide University Entrance Exam among all Iranian Student of Physics and Mathematics

 Jul 2015
- Qualified for the Second Round of Olympiad among more than 70K participants
 In the Iranian Physics Olympiad and Mathematical Olympiad

PUBLICATIONS

MEDIUM

- [1] <u>A. Yazdi</u>, "The Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter (part 1)", Using Software Engineering methods to design and build a fully responsive and adaptive mobile, desktop, and web application, *Flutter Community*, Jan 2021.
- [2] <u>A. Yazdi</u>, "The Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter (part 2)", Designing and building the Flutter application structure using the Bloc pattern in the micro-service architecture, *Flutter Community*, Jan 2021.
- [3] A. Yazdi, "The Software Engineering approach in Cross-Platform Programming with Flutter (part 3)", Designing and building the Flutter application data models and backend using the Build value and Bloc pattern, *Flutter Community*, Jan 2021.

PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

■ The Flutter Protfolio Application, Flutter

Designing and Building a responsive Flutter gallery application for any platform.

■ The Flutter Gallery Application, Flutter

Designing and Building a responsive Flutter gallery application for any platform using micro-service architecture.

■ The Flutter Media Notification Plugin, Java, Flutter

Designing and Building a Flutter Plugin that helps developers to show their media notification and control streaming media beyond their Flutter application.

■ The Location-Based Recommendation System, Django, Django Rest Framework, Scikit-learn, Flutter Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System with Djando and Flutter.

RESEARCH **INTERESTS**

- Artificial Intelligence
- Machine Learning
- Software Engineering

RESEARCH **EXPERIENCE**

Artificial Intelligent and Robotics Lab, Amirkabir University of Technology,

Oct 2019 - Oct 2020

- Undergraduate Research Student, Science Department
 - · Project: Designing and Implementing Location Based Social Network Recommendation System
 - Supervisors: Prof. Mohammad Rahmati
 - Focus: Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Data Analytics

LANGUAGES

- Persian: Native language
- English: Fluent, working proficiency

TECHNICAL SKILLS

■ Programming Languages

Dart, Python, Java, C/C++, PHP, Assembly

■ Mobile Development

Flutter, Android

■ Database Systems

PostgreSQL, MySQL

Operating System

Linux (Ubuntu)

■ Web Development

Django, Django Rest Framework

Other

Microcontroller Programming, Bash Scripting

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

■ **Programming Languages**, racket

NUMEX-Interpreter: Designing a simple interpreter NUMEX programming language with Racket.

■ **Information Security**, python

My-Security-Course: Encryption with MD5, SHA256, DES, working with cryptool software nmap and using ms08_067 exploitand.

■ Computer Networks, python

DNS-UDP-TCP-Proxy: A python proxy that receives HTTP packets on UDP then sends them on TCP with DNS server.

■ Microprocessor & Assembly Language, C

Digital-Watch-with-LCD: A digital watch with LCD and alarm using microcontroller ATMEGA16.

■ Data Structure & Algorithms, Java

Finite-State-Machine: Creating four types of data structure and searching using AVL-tree, balance-TST, trie-tree and hash.

■ Advanced Computer Programmings, Java

Planet-vs-Zombies: A 2d game similar to Plant vs Zombies game using java object oriented programming.

[Last Update on 2021-01-12]